Finding Aid for Michigan Football Centennial Committee records, 1978-1981
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Football Centennial Committee records 1978-1981
Michigan Football Centennial Committee
0.8 linear feet
85294 Br 2
Committee established to celebrate 100th anniversary of University of Michigan football; files relating to U-M football and to the work of the committee.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from the chairman of the committee, Paul Bigby (donor no. 6508 ) and came to the library in December 1982.
The record group is open to research.
The University of Michigan Football Centennial Committee was created August, 1978 to coordinate the activities associated with the 100th year celebration of University of Michigan football in 1979. George O. Hackett organized the first meeting and served as the Centennial Committee's initial chairman. After Hackett's June 1979 resignation, Paul Bigby replaced him as chairman and served in this capacity until the committee ceased functioning. Other executive committee members included Donald B. Canham, George R. Cavender, Robert G. Forman, Will Perry, and Michael Radock. Many alumni as well as Millie Schembechler participated in the nearly twenty ad hoc committees responsible for preparations.
Celebratory activities were held throughout the 1979 football season. A Centennial Kick-off Banquet, Memorabilia Exhibit, and mock staging of University of Michigan's first football game (with Racine College, 1879) were some of the celebration activities. October homecoming was commemorated with a Go Blue Brunch and special parade. Updates on Michigan's All-American players were featured throughout the events, and souvenirs with the '100 years of UM football theme' were made available for purchase.
The records of the Michigan Football Centennial Committee measure 0.8 linear feet and document the life of the organization from August 7, 1978 to April 9, 1981. The record group has been arranged into two principle series of materials: papers concerning the history of UM football, and records of the Michigan Football Centennial Committee.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Anniversaries, etc.; University of Michigan--Football.; Michigan Football Centennial Committee.
Contributors:
Bigby, Paul.
- History of University of Michigan Football
  The first series - history of UM football - includes the booklet published by the Committee, University of Michigan Football, 1879-1979, as well as related articles, anecdotes, and miscellaneous items.
  - University of Michigan Football, 1879-1979 (Box 1)
  - Racine College vs. Michigan, 1879 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (articles, anecdotes, etc.) (Box 1)
- University of Michigan Centennial Committee
  The second series - records of the Centennial Committee -includes correspondence, membership lists, planning reports, minutes, press releases, newsclippings, broadsides and ephemera, and other materials relating to the administration of the various program activities. Here are all items relevant to the organization and operation of the Committee, as well as those detailing program planning, fund raising, and public relations. The bulk of this series consists of correspondence among the executive committee members. This material is arranged into two chronological sequences: Hackett's papers while chairman, and organizational correspondence. Of special note is the final report of the committee, which is important because it summarizes the work and finances of the Michigan Football Centennial Committee.
  - Final Report, April 9, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Membership List (Box 1)
  - Planning Reports, Agendas, and Minutes, circa October 1978-May 1980 (Box 1)
  - George O. Hackett, Chairman
    - August 1978-March 1979 (Box 1)
    - April 1979-June 1979 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - 1978 (Box 1)
    - February-June 1979 (Box 1)
    - July-September 1979 (Box 1)
    - October-December 1979 (Box 1)
    - 1980 (Box 1)
  - Program Activities
    - Centennial Kick-off Banquet, September 8, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Memorabilia Exhibit, September 8, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Go Blue Brunch, October 27, 1979 (Box 1)
    - All-American Homecoming Parade, October 27, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Souvenir Book (Box 1)
    - Related Materials (Box 1)
  - Broadsides and Ephemera
    - Clippings (Box 1)
    - Marching Band participation (Box 1)
    - Michigan Captains (Box 1)
    - Michigan Greatest Fans (Box 1)
    - Public Relations materials, March-October 1979 (Box 1)
    - Replies to first questionnaire (Box 1)
    - University of Michigan Centennial Fund (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)